Hey everyone and thanks for jumping back
into the heavy metal verse.
Today, we're going to talk about gold as
it is now trading below 4,000.
Um I am going out of town next week, so
by the time you watch this video, I'm
not really sure exactly where it's going
to be trading, but it's around $4,000 um
per ounce. And so I just wanted to do an
update here. Again, in terms of
seasonality, we would expect corrections
throughout the midterm year. This is
what we talked about going into this
year was that we would likely get a
sizeable correction in the midterm year
for gold. Right now, it's down about
30% or so. Now, in terms of how far it
will go down,
it's honestly really difficult to know
exactly the sort of like the level that
it that it will drop. If you look at at
the drop we had in 2022, it was about a
22% drop. Um in some of the prior bull
markets of the past, uh if you look at
like 2008, you can see gold dropped
about 34% before bottoming. If you go
even further back and and look at 2006,
you can see that gold dropped about 26%
uh in in that bull market. And so the
question is is like, you know, I I think
that after the low forms in the midterm
year, I think that the gold bull market
could theoretically continue into the
end of the decade. Um
obviously when the bounce comes, I will
try to assess whether that
assessment is actually correct or not.
Uh but right now, I think it's more
important to figure out the sort of the
timing of the low rather than exactly
where the low is cuz it's it's
the window of weakness is a lot easier
to identify than exactly how far down it
has to go before it's actually going to
start showing some strength. And when
you again, when you just kind of provide
an update, when you look at the
year-to-date ROI of gold
in midterm years,
and let's say look at 2026, compare that
to 2022,
this is exactly where gold was. It just
feels worse this time because we came
from more elevated levels, but this is
where gold was.
In 2023, you can see gold started
trending back up again.
And in 2024 and in 2025, but the midterm
year was pretty weak. And in the midterm
year back then, gold bottomed in late
September of 2022.
In 2018, gold bottomed in about
mid-August. And you can also see that
we're kind of lined up with 2018 as
well.
And when you average out 2018 and 2022,
we can do that very, very quickly.
You can see that we're right at the
average of the last two midterm years.
And on average, they bottomed in the
August to September
time frame.
So,
I'm still going to run with this base
case that the low will occur sometime
between now and like kind of between the
July to October window.
The reason it could be as early as July
is because if you average out all prior
midterm years,
what you'll see is that Bitcoin
throughout all prior midterm years on
average bottoms out in early July.
So, in terms of the timing, I would say
July to October is the most likely time
for the low to occur and then for us to
build off of that going into the
pre-election year. Now, when you look at
gold, here's the shorter-term bull
market support band, which we use for
Bitcoin, but for gold, arguably, this is
not the right one to use. Gold moves a
lot slower, so we have the gold bull
market support band, and that's
getting really close to where the price
is. So, that's currently at around
3,800.
Not to say we can't go below it. We we
did go below it in 2022 just briefly. We
also briefly went below it in 2008.
Um so I I'm not here to say that it it
can't ever go below it, but it is one of
those things that we haven't really
checked in with it in a while. The last
time we checked in with it was in 2023.
So, look for that. Look for that to
happen here in the coming weeks, at
least for us to get relatively close to
it if not tag it. And and then from
around those levels, I would expect some
type of low to try and form. As measured
from the current price, that's about a
4% drop in order to get there. But
remember, the moving average could come
up to us, rather than us going to that.
But about a 4% drop, when you look at
the year-to-date ROI of Bitcoin um in
2026 and compare it to 2022 and 2018,
you know, right now, as measured from
the yearly open, uh Bitcoin, or sorry,
gold is about 5 or 6% down. And in the
last two midterm years, around the lows,
we were down closer to about, say, 10 to
11%. So, all of that would actually be
in line with kind of what we've seen and
and even with that that longer-term bull
market support band.
So, let's see if gold kind of continues
to do what it always does. Hopefully, we
can see gold find some type of a support
in this area
between July and October. And from those
levels, I would I would look for it to
to start expanding back out again,
hopefully going to a new higher high.
But we'll take that one step at a time.
Those are my views on on gold.
Obviously, silver has taken a pretty big
hit recently. It is actually now at that
bull market support band. But the reason
I haven't made as many videos about
silver is because I I I I made a video
back about it in in in February,
basically saying, "Look, guys, the the
gold-silver ratio is really low. And so,
now we would expect gold to outperform
silver for for while." And and you can
see that it has, right? So, gold has
just been a better play than silver even
though they've both been going down,
silver's obviously gone down a lot more.
And I think silver could could draw some
more attention after the gold bottom is
actually in. As long as gold continues
sort of go down, silver could continue
to underperform. But once that low for
gold is set, I think things will will,
you know, could very well start to
change.
Um so, that's why I haven't been
following up so much with silver. But
remember, one of the things I mentioned
with silver quite a long time ago was
that you would likely see it kind of
back test or get close to the the prior
tops, and we're actually getting really
close to that. So, uh keep an eye on
silver, too. Recognize that it is
bleeding to gold, and that bleed could
go on for a a little bit longer. Um but
it all kind of aligns when you look at
it, I think, in an objective and
unbiased way. It It's just hard when
you're kind of living through the
drawdowns and and seeing and then people
want to try to call the bottom, but it's
really hard to know exactly where that
bottom's going to be.
The argument being that, you know,
these prior highs were always sort of
like a level to keep in mind. And if it
goes below that level, then I think that
would be sort of a
a deep value zone if silver were to head
down below uh below 50 bucks per ounce.
Again, now I still think it's a little
bit premature because even if the bottom
is in for silver,
you know, I you would argue that it
okay, it's like the '70s where it it
came back down to the bull market's
weapon, but it didn't really go anywhere
for a while, right? Like it just bounced
off of it for a year or so, a couple of
years before then going up uh once more.
So, those are my views on gold. Thank
you guys for tuning in. Uh if if you
haven't signed up for the ITC conference
yet, I would encourage you to do so. I
think it's going to be a pretty good
time. We're going to talk about Bitcoin,
gold, the the, you know, equities, uh a
lot of different things. We're going to
have a lot of great speakers there. So,
hopefully you guys will will Hopefully,
I'll see you guys there. Uh November
20th through the 22nd in Miami. Links
down in the description below and the
pinned comment. Thank you guys for
tuning in. Subscribe and I'll see you
next time. Bye.